In this clip we are going to go over the different types of bleeding that can occur and the different aspects of treating it.
There are three different types of bleeding that you should be aware of.
What they are is capillary, venous and also arterial.
Capillary bleeding is one of the most minor.
It usually requires no intervention at all.
That can be something such as a rug burn or what we call an abrasion where you have actually torn the skin off and you have what is an oozing type of blood coming out.
Next is a venous type of blood.
Venous blood will normally be dark and it's normally going to be a nice steady constant flow of blood.
That's what most people see and it's pretty common.
The last type is our arterial bleed.
This one is very important because it's a major life threat and you could die from it very quickly.
Arterial blood is the bleed is described as bright red squirting blood.
This will come in spirits with every time your heart beats.
It's important that when you come across an arterial bleed that you immediately go for the steps of treatment.
What that would include would be first direct pressure, elevation, pressure point and last is the tunicate.